Music
音楽
rate
レート
The important activities of the school to promote science popularization have been going on for many years. Every month, there are forests, biology, humanities, and mountain masters. Scholars and experts from inside and outside the hospital are invited to watch.
科学の普及を促進するための学校の重要な活動は長年続いており、毎月、森林、生物学、人文科学、山岳師が開催され、病院内外の学者や専門家が招待されています。
We are very happy and honored today
今日はとても嬉しく光栄です
Please go to the Humanities and Social Sciences Research Center of our hospital
当院人文社会科学研究センターへお越しください。
Dr. Xiao Gaoyuan came to talk to you
シャオ・ガオユアン博士があなたに話をしに来ました
Is democracy a universal value
民主主義は普遍的な価値観なのか
Dr. Hsiao is a member of the Department of Political Science, National Taiwan University
シャオ博士は国立台湾大学政治学部のメンバーです。
Graduated from Political Science Institute
政治学院卒業
Then went to Yale University for Ph.D.
その後エール大学に博士号取得に進学。
After I came back, I was at the Academia Sinica
帰国後は中央研究院にいました
Zhongshan Institute of Humanities and Social Sciences Cognitive
中山人文社会科学研究所認知
Later, after Zhongshan Humanities and Social Sciences was changed to the Center for Humanities and Social Sciences
その後、中山人文社会科学センターは人文社会科学センターに変更されました。
he's always there
彼はいつもそこにいる
Currently a researcher at the institute
現在、同研究所の研究員
Bing is also the executive director of the Research Center for Political Thought
ビング氏は政治思想研究センターのエグゼクティブディレクターでもある
At the same time, he is also the member of the academic executive committee of the college.
同時に、彼は大学の学術執行委員会のメンバーでもあります。
deputy executive secretary
副執行秘書
Professor Xiao's field of research is
シャオ教授の研究分野は
History of Western Political Thought and Contemporary Political Philosophy
西洋政治思想史と現代政治哲学
His doctoral dissertation was dealing with
彼の博士論文は次のことを扱っていました
Hegel's Ethics and Politics
ヘーゲルの倫理と政治
China's early research on contemporary political theory issues
現代政治理論問題に関する中国の初期研究
communitarianism
共同体主義
and related issues of social identity in Taiwan
台湾における社会的アイデンティティとそれに関連する問題
In a short time after Professor Xiao returned to China
シャオ教授が中国に帰国してからしばらくして
Just because an article was published in the most important political science journal in the West
論文が西側で最も重要な政治学雑誌に掲載されたという理由だけで
Contact Award from the National Science Council
米国科学会議からの賞を受賞
I was told so far
ここまで言われてた
There are only three articles published by domestic scholars in that journal
その雑誌に国内の学者によって掲載された論文はわずか 3 件だけです
Well, this is the first time I heard the name of Professor Xiao
シャオ先生の名前は初めて聞きました
In the past ten years or so, he has started with the history of thought and political analysis
ここ10年ほどは思想史や政治分析からスタート
Research on the historical evolution and theoretical significance of Western republicanism
西洋共和主義の歴史的展開と理論的意義に関する研究
There is already a book of five or six hundred pages that will be published by a certain publishing house soon
すでに500ページか600ページの本があり、近々出版社から出版される予定です
What about Professor Xiao?
シャオ先生はどうですか？
Because he is here today, I dare not speak too exaggerated language
今日は彼が来ているので、あまり大袈裟な言葉はあえて言いません
Well, if he's not here, I'm going to say
まあ、彼がここにいないなら、私は言うつもりです
He's actually a lot of people who have told me
実際、彼は私にそう言ってくれた人がたくさんいます
He is our most important student of the history of Western political thought
彼は西洋政治思想史における私たちの最も重要な研究者です
loud voice he's on so i speak one
彼が大きな声を出しているので、私が一つ話します
hope it didn't trouble him
それが彼を困らせなかったことを願う
Democracy is one everyone knows
民主主義は誰もが知っているもの
But everyone hasn't read a full
でもみんなまだ全部読んでいない
title of book on democracy and liberty
民主主義と自由に関する本のタイトル
Originally, the topic of thought was very difficult to talk about.
もともと思想というテーマは非常に話しにくいものでした。
Personally, I never had the courage to speak out.
私自身、声を上げる勇気がありませんでした。
problems in this area
この分野の問題
because it is a feast of knowledge
それは知識の饗宴だからです
talk about things that are too thoughtful and too philosophical
あまりにも思慮深く哲学的なことについて話す
Difficult to hold the audience's attention
聴衆の注意を引くのが難しい
but today i believe
でも今日は信じます
I hope you have enough attention
十分な注意を払っていただければ幸いです
But I think Professor Xiao will be able to complete this task
でも、シャオ先生ならこの仕事をやり遂げられると思います
Give a successful speech on Western political thought
西洋の政治思想についてのスピーチを成功させる
His topic today is Is Democracy a Universal Value?
今日の彼のテーマは「民主主義は普遍的価値か?」です。
as far as i talked to him earlier
以前彼と話した限りでは
The most important thing for him is to discuss with you
彼にとって最も重要なことはあなたと話し合うことです
How does democracy go from a
民主主義はどうやって生まれるのか
Turns out there were negative reviews
否定的なレビューがあったことが判明
then slowly evolved into
その後ゆっくりと進化していきました
Democracy is now a universal value throughout history
民主主義は今や歴史を通じて普遍的な価値観となっている
Let's welcome the professor with warm applause
温かい拍手で教授をお迎えしましょう
Thank you, Vice President, Hello, everyone.
副社長、ありがとうございます、皆さん、こんにちは。
Well I am very happy to have this opportunity today
さて、今日はこのような機会をいただけてとても嬉しいです
Let me discuss with you whether this democracy is a universal value.
この民主主義が普遍的な価値観であるかどうかについて議論させてください。
such a topic
そんな話題
Then what Chen Rufei Yanggang just said
では、陳如飛楊剛が今言ったことは
This feast of knowledge is aimed at audiences of many levels
この知識の饗宴は、さまざまなレベルの聴衆を対象としています
Well, this is actually the first time I've given a public speech
実は、人前で演説するのはこれが初めてなんです
So maybe lack of experience
だから経験不足なのかもしれない
Then I will try my best to use Taiwan's experience
台湾の経験を活かして頑張ります
And the entry of some ideas of this daily life
そして、この日常生活の中にいくつかのアイデアが入ります
But there are still a lot of unavoidable content
しかし、それでも避けられない内容はたくさんあります
This one of my majors
これは私の専攻の 1 つです
That is, hope is really like some concepts in the middle
つまり、希望は実際には中間のいくつかの概念のようなものです
and an explanation of its rheology
そしてそのレオロジーの説明
But I hope that after the explanation
しかし、説明が終わったら、
able to have some
いくつか持つことができる
We might end up at the end for half an hour
最後は30分くらいかかるかもしれない
Teach Me PowerPoint
パワーポイントを教えてください
Then I suddenly finished
そしたら突然終わってしまった
that may have more time
そのほうが時間はあるかもしれない
we have more time to do a
もっと時間があります
a free discussion
自由な議論
Then I am for democracy
それなら私は民主主義を支持します
We only need one now
今必要なのは 1 つだけです
very simple one to start with
とてもシンプルなスタート
without a very complicated definition
非常に複雑な定義なしで
Democracy in the language of the West
西洋の言語での民主主義
It is Demo
デモです
Democracy is Demo and Kratia
民主主義はデモとクラティアです
It's the word Kratis
それはクラティスという言葉です
it is a greek
それはギリシャ人です
So Demos represent a meaning of the people
つまりデモは人々の意味を表すのです
Then the word Kratia is basically
それでは、クラティアという言葉は基本的には
Power or Authority
権力または権威
the rights of the people
人々の権利
It represents a right of the people
それは人々の権利を表します
or the rule of the people
あるいは民衆のルールか
so its this
それでこれです
such a definition
そのような定義
no need
必要なし
there is a very specific one
非常に具体的なものがあります
a sign of the system
システムの兆候
so so democratic
とても民主的
not just for orientals or chinese
東洋人や中国人だけではない
or Taiwanese
または台湾人
When I first came into contact with Western thought
初めて西洋思想に触れたとき
or cultural time
または文化的な時間
It may be very difficult to imagine the concept of democracy
民主主義の概念を想像するのは非常に難しいかもしれません
even if
もしそれでも
even the west itself
西そのものさえも
One thing I want to talk about today is that
今日話したいことの一つは、
the concept of democracy
民主主義の概念
Well it's not just in the rest of our society
まあ、それは私たちの社会の他の部分だけではありません
by learning
学ぶことによって
and interpretation
そして解釈
and implement it in our local environment
そしてそれをローカル環境に実装します
in the western world
西洋の世界で
in the history of thought
思想史の中で
and in actual politics
そして実際の政治においても
It actually went through the same process
実際には同じプロセスを経ます
So democracy is a very special value
つまり民主主義は非常に特別な価値観なのです
then i hope i can today
だから今日はできるといいな
take it slow and talk it out
ゆっくり話し合ってください
So of course democracy is a universal value
もちろん民主主義は普遍的な価値観です
this universal value
この普遍的な価値観を
Or sometimes we translate into universal values
あるいは、普遍的な価値観に変換することもあります
Then of course we say that democracy is a universal value
もちろん、民主主義は普遍的な価値観であると言います
or a universal value
あるいは普遍的な価値観
it doesn't mean
それは意味がありません
For example, we say that the force of gravity
たとえば、重力は次のように言います。
is a universal concentration
普遍的な集中力です
not a universal in the sense
ある意味では普遍的ではない
a universal
普遍的な
but we see now
しかし、今はわかります
In a current public discourse
現在の公の場での議論の中で
so let's say it
だから言ってみましょう
that means we would say
つまり、こう言うことになります
Values ​​that every rational citizen should accept
すべての合理的な市民が受け入れるべき価値観
why i use this quotes
なぜこの引用を使うのか
or English quotation
または英語の引用
Because this is contemporary political philosophy
これは現代の政治哲学だから
Some of the more specific ways of expressing
より具体的な表現方法をいくつか挙げると、
it means to say
それは言うことを意味します
we are talking about democracy
私たちは民主主義について話しています
or when the universality of political values
あるいは政治的価値観の普遍性が高まったとき
we didn't try to make it
私たちはそれを達成しようとしたわけではありません
scientists or even logic
科学者や論理さえも
or a generality in the mathematical sense
または数学的な意味での一般性
but
しかし
course political philosopher
もちろん政治哲学者
they will use some different ways
彼らはいくつかの異なる方法を使用するでしょう
a design for some discourses
いくつかの言説のデザイン
to illustrate that a rational citizen should
理性的な市民がすべきことを説明するために
This should of course be the absolute question right here
もちろん、これがここでの絶対的な質問であるはずです
So what about the report I'm waiting for?
それで、私が待っているレポートはどうなるでしょうか？
will speak out slowly
ゆっくりと声を出します
That is to say, in the long history of democratic thought
つまり、民主主義思想の長い歴史の中で、
come and tell us
来て私たちに教えてください
a reasonable person
合理的な人
A rational person should accept the democratic
合理的な人は民主主義を受け入れるべきです
Where is the argument for this value
この値の引数はどこですか
So the meaning of a question in my speech
私のスピーチの質問の意味は
like this
このような
Then the vice president just mentioned briefly
それから、先ほど副大統領が簡単に言いました。
Which means we just have to go back and look at history
つまり、過去に戻って歴史を振り返る必要があるということです
Looking at the context of history
歴史の流れを見てみると
We say that democracy has universal values
私たちは民主主義には普遍的な価値があると言います
is a very established thing
それは非常に確立されたものです
Because human beings in this world have been
なぜなら、この世界の人類は、
Almost most people live in
ほぼほとんどの人が住んでいます
democracy or aristocracy
民主主義か貴族主義か
or other systems
または他のシステム
or dictatorship
あるいは独裁政権
Democratic society in human society
人間社会における民主主義社会
Only in the very ancient Greek democracy
非常に古代ギリシャの民主主義においてのみ
existed for about two hundred years
約二百年にわたって存在した
And then when it's seen as after
そしてその後を考えると
not only in the western world
西側世界だけでなく
anywhere else in the world
世界中のどこでも
except very local
ごくローカルなものを除いて
That is to say, there are some habits of democracy
つまり、民主主義にはいくつかの習慣があるということです。
Then when we talk about democratic politics at scale
それでは、大規模な民主政治について話すとき、
does not exist
存在しない
but it was around the eighteenth century
でもそれは18世紀頃のことでした
began to gradually rise in the context of the West
西洋の文脈の中で徐々に台頭し始めた
Gradually collide
徐々に衝突する
until almost the twentieth century
ほぼ20世紀まで
when we were in the second half of the twentieth century
私たちが20世紀後半にいたとき
Especially the issue of national universality
特に国家の普遍性の問題
Especially after the collapse of the socialist state
特に社会主義国家崩壊後は
From the late 1980s to the 1990s
1980年代後半から1990年代にかけて
what about that time
その時はどうですか
Due to a collapse of this ideology of socialism
この社会主義イデオロギーの崩壊により
Then let the Western world produce a
それなら西洋世界に何かを生み出させましょう
OK, in that state
はい、その状態で
So is the value of politics already basically
政治の価値も基本的にはすでにそうなっている
In addition to liberal democracy
自由民主主義に加えて
That's what they're talking about now I'll talk about it later
それが今彼らが話していることです、それについては後で話します
A procedural, a liberal democracy, a concept outside
手続き主義、自由民主主義、外側の概念
Then the ideology that competes with him
そして彼と競合するイデオロギー
Basically it's all gone
基本的には全部なくなった
Then such a statement was made in the first half of the night in the 1990s
1990年代の深夜、このような発言がなされた
is very very popular
とてもとても人気があります
When I was studying in the United States, there were many discourses on
私が米国に留学していたとき、次のような議論がたくさんありました。
with a very
とても
very triumphant tone
とても勝ち誇った口調
a historical purpose
歴史的な目的
Like when I was doing research and Hegel said
私が研究をしていたときにヘーゲルが言ったときのように
Hegel has a famous saying
ヘーゲルには有名な言葉があります
Said that history is the process of displaying the spirit of freedom
歴史は自由の精神を示す過程であると述べた
A very practical statement like this
このような非常に実践的な発言
in the late 90s
90年代後半に
actually there
実際にそこにあります
sorry early 90s
ごめんなさい90年代初頭
Also in public forums in the US
米国の公開討論会でも
After a package
パッケージの後
Become a human history has reached an end
人類の歴史は終わりを迎えた
This end point is beyond Liberal democracy
この終着点は自由民主主義を超えています
it's hard for you to imagine
あなたには想像するのが難しいです
The other value system is the universal one value
もう一つの価値体系は普遍的な価値観です
If you know one of those days
もしあの頃を知っていたら
words of public discourse
公の場での談話の言葉
will know that there is a man named Fukuyama
福山という男がいることを知るだろう
Fukuyama Scholars
福山奨学生
put forward such an argument
そのような議論を提起する
That is a Hegelian language
それはヘーゲルの言語です
Come to the contemporary forum in the United States
米国のコンテンポラリーフォーラムにお越しください
when socialism collapsed
社会主義が崩壊したとき
Some remarks made
いくつかの発言があった
Can face the phenomenon of democracy
民主主義という現象に直面できる
It actually has a contradiction
実は矛盾してる
This contradiction means that
この矛盾が意味するのは、
On the one hand, it is historically
一方で、歴史的には
very later
とても後になって
Is of course it when starting with historical experience
歴史的な経験から始める場合はもちろんです
in the western world
西洋の世界で
is very much an afterthought
それは非常に後付けの考えです
But a value of our current politics
しかし、私たちの現在の政治の価値観
or a moral sub bureau
または道徳支局
when we ask ourselves
私たちが自分自身に問いかけるとき
Democracy is not our own true value when
民主主義は私たち自身の真の価値ではありません。
Most people will answer
ほとんどの人が答えるでしょう
Yes means that this universality
Yes はこの普遍性を意味します
in many countries
たくさんの国で
Until now
今まで
Already compared to the late 1980s
すでに1980年代後半と比較
The Disintegration of Socialism in the Early 1990s
1990年代初頭の社会主義の崩壊
Until now
今まで
The degree of support for such a view
そうした見方に対する支持の度合い
In fact, it is getting higher and higher
実はどんどん高くなっています
Then I insert a
次に、を挿入します
Chinese and democratic such a
中国人と民主主義のような
power point means
パワーポイントの意味
Democracy is unimaginable
民主主義なんて想像もつかない
then in the nineteenth century
それから19世紀に
When we first started contacting the West
私たちが初めて西側諸国と接触し始めたとき
It is not easy to imagine the meaning of democracy
民主主義の意味を想像するのは簡単ではない
So so in the nineteenth century
19世紀もそうだった
In the second half of the night, during the time of Yin and Han
殷漢時間の深夜の真ん中
This concept was once forced
この概念はかつては強制されていた
translated into multiplayer
マルチプレイヤーに変換
A lot of people mess with the tube
チューブをいじる人が多い
Or the petty people take power
さもなければ小市民が権力を握る
There are many other ways
他にもたくさんの方法があります
Then until the beginning of the twentieth century
それから20世紀初頭まで
in a very short time
非常に短い時間で
About ten or twenty years
10年か20年くらい
then he is stabilized
そうすれば彼は安定する
That is to say, to remove such a
つまり、そのようなものを取り除くには、
judgment of value
価値判断
translated into civil affairs
民事に翻訳される
or democracy, etc.
あるいは民主主義など。
Not only that
それだけでなく
He is less than twenty years old
彼は20歳未満です
Then in the samurai movement
その後、武士の運動の中で
Mr. De
彼はデ氏として請求されました
Of course we are well aware of the history of this
もちろん、私たちはその歴史をよく知っています
There are many advanced
先進的なものがたくさんあります
Also did a lot of research
また、たくさんの研究をしました
The so-called Mr. De
いわゆるデさん
Mr. Sai Democracy
サイ・デモクラシー氏
and Science
と科学
is considered to be one of the rescuers of China
中国の救援者の一人とみなされている
Bolfamen
ボルファメン
i sometimes think
私は時々思う
I have not done research
研究はしていない
Why didn't they talk about freedom and science?
なぜ当時彼らは自由と科学について語らなかったのでしょうか？
there must be a special reason for this
これには特別な理由があるに違いありません
Is there some sense of democracy in
民主主義の感覚はあるのか
chance above
上のチャンス
on the root
根元に
There is some kind of power that touches people's hearts
人の心を動かす何かの力がある
Of course we can come back slowly
もちろんゆっくり戻ってきてもいいよ
discuss this matter
この問題について話し合う
then this is a
それならこれは
A few weeks ago I went to a
数週間前に私はあるところへ行きました
I was invited to comment on a
あるコメントに招待されました
A technical article
技術的な記事
It's not really my specialty
それは実際には私の専門ではありません
but in this place
でもこの場所では
it is a survey
それは調査です
It is a survey of East Asian values
東アジアの価値観に関する調査です
A Thing That Investigates Democratic Values
民主主義の価値観を調査するもの
we invite you to watch this
ぜひご覧ください
this problem
この問題
He said democracy may have its problem
彼は民主主義には問題があるかもしれないと述べた
but it is still the best form of government
しかし、それは依然として最良の政府形態である
This respondent was asked the question
この回答者は質問されました
answer this question
この質問に答えてください
Yes is 76.18
はいは76.18です
such a number
そんな数字
Then such a number
そうすると、こんな数字が
Let's look at the support degree
サポート度を見てみよう
it is almost the highest
ほぼ最高です
It's the same as this one except
それ以外はこれと同じです
Which country did the respondent answer?
回答者はどの国と答えましたか?
this is mainland china
ここは中国本土です
It is man in China
中国の男です
Well then I'll comment on that article
それではその記事にコメントさせていただきます
Nothing to do with today's topic
今日の話題とは関係ありません
because for him
なぜなら彼にとっては
It produces a very interesting puzzle
非常に興味深いパズルが生まれます
because he said
彼が言ったから
Another problem is
もう一つの問題は
I would prefer live under our system of government
私は私たちの統治システムの下で生きたいと思っています
any other than I can think of
私が思いつく以外に
He replied that freedom is the best system
彼は自由が最良のシステムだと答えた
Then you can live under this system in mainland China
そうすれば中国本土でもこの制度のもとで生活できるようになる
so they empirical people
それで彼らは経験主義者です
That is to say, those who make this empirical theory should return
つまり、この経験論を主張する者は立ち返るべきである。
I want to ask if this is a fake
これが偽物かどうか聞きたい
or he is cheating
それとも彼が浮気しているのか
Or he's going to make one of these two numbers
あるいは、彼はこれら 2 つの数字のうちの 1 つを作るつもりです
make a bond
絆を結ぶ
Said he was going to offer an explanation
彼は説明をするつもりだと言った
Why do people in mainland China
中国本土の人々はなぜ
He himself believes that democracy is a
彼自身、民主主義とは
best value ratio
最良の価値の比率
so tall but he
とても背が高いけど、彼は
Basically accept the authoritarian rule of mainland China
中国本土の権威主義的統治を基本的に受け入れる
That's not one of our topics today
それは今日の話題ではありません
All we're going to see is the
私たちが見るのは、
A country like mainland China
中国本土のような国
Then democracy is also a highly supported
それから民主主義も非常に支持されています
recognized one
一つ認識した
one political value
一つの政治的価値観
So
それで
I will introduce the following Powerpoints to you
以下のパワーポイントを紹介します。
I have one for you
あなたに一つ持っています
the blue version
ブルーバージョン
is one of my speeches online
これは私のオンラインでのスピーチの 1 つです
Then you can refer to
その後、参照できます
that is
あれは
the one that put a backbone of my speech
私のスピーチの根幹をなすもの
put it there
そこにそれを置きます
But the main text because
しかし、本文は、
Because of space
スペースのせいで
I still only put it on the Powerpoint side
まだパワーポイント側にしか載せてないです
so
それで
in the following words
次の言葉で
Then based on an experience in Taiwan
そして台湾での経験をもとに
Let me introduce to you
ご紹介しましょう
How do we view democracy in Taiwan
台湾の民主主義をどう見るか
So one of the key points of this issue is to say
したがって、この問題の重要なポイントの 1 つは次のとおりです。
Let's go to Taiwan's public discourse
台湾の討論会に行こう
I'm just very simple
私はとても単純です
As far as I can remember, I took two paragraphs of text
私が覚えている限り、テキストは 2 段落分ありました
Then you can see
そうすればわかります
Can't see where this text comes from
このテキストの出所がわかりません
Then the first paragraph
それから最初の段落
this is a quarter
これは四半期です
it is a cryptogram
それは暗号文です
He said Taiwan's democracy dilemma was never really implemented
同氏は、台湾の民主主義のジレンマは実際には実現されなかったと述べた
constitutionalism
的憲政主義constitutionalism
This is the spirit of the original text
これが原文の精神です
Constitutionalism emphasizes separation of powers and checks and balances
立憲主義は権力分立と抑制と均衡を重視する
Advocating the Rule of Law and Defending Basic Human Rights
法の支配を提唱し、基本的人権を擁護する
And strict constitutional government must not abuse power
そして厳格な憲政は権力を乱用してはならない
This is the necessary foundation for a good democracy
これは良い民主主義に必要な基盤です
However, in the time zone where democracy was in Taiwan
しかし、台湾が民主主義だった時間帯では、
biased towards elections
選挙に偏っている
The essence of democracy
民主主義の本質
The idea of ​​constitutionalism
立憲主義の考え方
not paying enough attention to
十分な注意を払っていない
As a result, except for politicians who violated the law and abused their power
その結果、政治家が法律を破ったり権力を乱用したりすることは別として、
All walks of life except greed
貪欲を除くあらゆる職業
Jin can't make a difference
ジンは何も変えられない
So in modern times this is continuous
つまり現代でもこれは継続的です
modern western democracy
現代西洋民主主義
even developed successfully because
開発にも成功したので、
Keep the spirit of constitutionalism first
立憲主義の精神を第一に
Constitutionalism asserts that everyone has inalienable fundamental rights
立憲主義は、すべての人が不可侵の基本的権利を持っていると主張します
Government rights must be limited
政府の権利は制限されなければならない
the constitution of the law makes everyone equal
法律の憲法はすべての人を平等にする
follow the law
法律に従います
The administrative system is strictly neutral
行政システムは厳密に中立です
These are the basic principles of a democracy against
これらは民主主義の基本原則です。
Despotism or populism please note this opposition
専制主義かポピュリズムか、この反対に注意してください
we'll talk about that later
それについては後で話します
The key is that this is what we pursue for high-quality democracy
重要なのは、これが私たちが質の高い民主主義を追求することであるということです
do guarantee
保証します
So he went on to say that after he came to power
それで彼は権力を握った後、こう続けた
All efforts to implement the core value of democracy are
民主主義の中核的価値を実現するためのあらゆる努力は、
Constitutionalism has become the consensus of ruling and opposition parties
立憲主義は与野党の合意となった
We look forward to the DPP, of course this is President Ma
民進党を楽しみにしています、もちろん馬総統です。
A white arm of this constitutional reform at the time of the first election
初選挙時の憲法改正の白腕
still available online
まだオンラインで入手可能
Then we expect the DPP not to be subject to
その場合、民進党は規制の対象にならないと予想されます。
Taiwanese democracy thereby abandoning their commitment to
それによって台湾の民主主義は、
Surveillance due to constitutional democracy
立憲民主主義による監視
We also advocate the addition of constitutionalism, nationalism, etc.
立憲主義、国家主義などを加えることも主張します。
This is a view of democracy
これが民主主義の考え方です
Well, this view is of course what we generally call
もちろん、この考え方は私たちが一般的に呼んでいるものです。
constitutional democracy
憲政民主
Then sometimes his value is Liber
そして時々彼の価値はLiberです
we are called
私たちは呼ばれています
Liber democracy is the constitutionalism of this democracy
自由民主主義はこの民主主義の立憲主義です
But Taiwan has other
しかし台湾には他にもある
There is another concept of democracy
民主主義には別の概念があります
the concept it says so
そう言うコンセプト
building the nation
国家を建設する
It advocates the construction of national sovereignty
国家主権の構築を主張している
Principles of National sovereignty
National sovereignty的原則
Create a modern constitutional state
近代立憲国家を創る
Do not touch the principle of national sovereignty
国家主権の原則には触れないでください
emphasize some governance
ある程度のガバナンスを強調する
between public opinion as a rule
原則として世論と世論の間
We recommend strengthening direct civil rights
直接公民権の強化を推奨します
establish the principle of national sovereignty
国家主権の原則を確立する
Let the people know about the law and the affairs of the country
国民に法律や国の事情を知らせる
criminal
犯罪的
create referendum
住民投票を作成する
It's ready now
もう準備完了です
then it goes on
それから続きます
or another paragraph
または別の段落
citizen hair will be 22 million
国民の髪の毛は2,200万になる
The people of Taiwan use it to fight against
台湾の人々はそれを使って戦う
Chinese regime on the other side
向こう側の中国政権
The most powerful force to annex Taiwan
台湾併合の最強勢力
also the last weapon
最終兵器でもある
even say
さえ言う
Even if the citizen's hair is Taiwan
たとえ国民の髪の毛が台湾であっても
The Last Trump Card of People's Governance
人民統治の最後の切り札
The last line of defense is not an exaggeration
最終防衛線と言っても過言ではない
then this is in
それならこれは中にあります
Ah Bian's constitutional policy white skin negligence
阿ビアンの憲法政策、白い肌の怠慢
before the first administration
最初の投与の前に
That is, it was proposed in the second millennium AD
つまり、西暦2千年紀に提案されました。
These two are very simple
この2つはとてもシンプルです
A discussion in a public forum
公開フォーラムでのディスカッション
Then their writers are scholars
その場合、彼らの作家は学者です
I think so but he lays it out nicely
そう思うけど、彼はそれをうまく表現している
That is to say, even in a place like Taiwan
つまり、台湾のような場所でも
in a democratic society
民主主義社会では
our value to democracy
民主主義に対する私たちの価値
concept of democracy
民主主義の概念
In fact, there is still a different understanding
実際にはまだ異なる理解があります
one way
一方通行
So are we going to say
それで、私たちは言うつもりですか
Democracy is an inherently contestable concept
民主主義は本質的に異論の余地のある概念である
so-called inherently contestable concepts
いわゆる本質的に議論の余地のある概念
a concept in political philosophy
政治哲学における概念
Called Essentially Contested Concept
本質的に争われているコンセプトと呼ばれる
For example, some concepts
たとえば、いくつかの概念
it's so controversial in itself
それ自体がとても物議を醸している
So it is never possible to achieve a
したがって、達成することは決して不可能です
a precise definition
正確な定義
which itself defines A must have another definition
それ自体が定義する A には別の定義が必要です
The definition opposed to it yields
これに反する定義は次のようになります。
so we call it an essentially contestable concept
したがって、私たちはそれを本質的に異論の余地のある概念と呼んでいます
Then let's look at the previous two videos
それでは、前の 2 つのビデオクリップを見てみましょう
constitutionalism versus national sovereignty
立憲主義と国家主権
Then populism should be reversed
ならばポピュリズムは逆転すべきだ
fundamental rights versus populism
基本的権利とポピュリズム
In fact, in the system of different political theories
実際、さまざまな政治理論の体系の中で、
can be an important element of democratic political theory
民主政治理論の重要な要素となり得る
But when it is placed in a different context
しかし、それが別の文脈に置かれると、
when it is combined with each other
お互いに組み合わせると
it produces a different context
異なるコンテキストが生成されます
Then it will also produce different
そうすれば、また別のものが生成されます
A this of public policy
公共政策のこれ
An account of this orientation, etc.
今回のオリエンテーションなどの説明。
so in other words
つまり、言い換えれば
Are these mutual democratic concepts Taiwan's
これらの相互民主主義の概念は台湾のものなのでしょうか？
unique
個性的
what am i talking about
何を言うつもりですか？
this is a
これは
This is a democratic political
これは民主的な政治です
or the history of the development of the concept of democracy
または民主主義の概念の発展の歴史
is a thing that has always existed
それは常に存在するものです
So democracy in the history of Western political thought
西洋政治思想史における民主主義
It is also a concept that is constantly changing
それは常に変化し続ける概念でもあります
But we will slowly see
でも、ゆっくり見ていきましょう
During the development of the history of the twentieth century
20世紀の歴史の発展の中で
its competitor is not democracy
その競争相手は民主主義ではない
please first
まずはお願いします
Let me tell you one clue first.
まず一つのヒントを教えてください。
That is to say, democracy is often overshadowed by its opponents
つまり、民主主義は反対者によって影が薄くなることが多いのです。
Defined by
によって定義されます
so
それで
The second century to the end when his universal
彼の普遍的な時代が終わるまでの2世紀
The so-called universal value is his antithesis
いわゆる普遍的価値観は彼のアンチテーゼである
After its own legitimacy slowly fades away
自らの正当性がゆっくりと消え去った後
A very unique phenomenon that arises
非常にユニークな現象が起こる
Will there be other historical forms in the future?
将来的には他の歴史的な形式も登場するのでしょうか？
Can compete with liberal democracy or democracy
自由民主主義や民主主義と競合できる
That's one thing I don't know
それは私が知らないことの一つです
but
しかし
Let's see what we've said so far
これまで述べてきたことを見てみましょう
is indeed a generation of such a general situation
確かにそのような一般的な状況の世代です
Then in the following
それでは以下で
I will enter into my speech and compare
私のスピーチに入って比較してみます
part of the academic
学問の一部
I will go with you as much as possible
可能な限り一緒に行きます
in an understandable way
わかりやすい方法で
Do an Intellectual History Review
知的歴史のレビューを行う
It is a review of the history of the idea of ​​democracy
民主主義の思想の歴史を振り返る
Then in all the development of political values
そして、あらゆる政治的価値観の発展において、
Democracy is characterized by a second coming
民主主義は再臨によって特徴づけられる
is a second coming
再臨です
Why is he a second coming
なぜ彼は再臨なのか
That is to say, the generation of political value
つまり、政治的価値の生成
Whether it is the East or the West
東でも西でも
In fact, generally speaking, it is actually a specific struggle
実際、一般的に言って、それは実際には特殊な闘争です
or class conflict
あるいは階級対立
or one of various
またはさまざまなうちの 1 つ
slowly emerged from a de facto political initiative
事実上の政治的イニシアチブからゆっくりと浮上してきた
Let's go for an example
例を挙げてみましょう
the concept of country
国の概念
The concept of the state itself is
国家という概念そのものが、
In fact in the English language
実は英語では
used for the first time in our present sense
現在の意味で初めて使われた
When the country is uncertain
国が不安定なとき
Almost at Hobbs' legislator talk
ほぼホッブズの議員講演の段階にある
That is, 1650
つまり1650年
Before 1650 there was of course the word State
1650 年以前には、もちろん「国家」という言葉がありました。
But that State it represents some status
しかし、その状態は何らかのステータスを表します
is its state
その状態です
Or it will become our current concept of State
あるいはそれが現在の国家概念になるだろう
Because it has a meaning of Political status
政治的地位の意味があるから
that is to say its political status
つまり政治的地位を意味する
For example, the political state of a monarch
たとえば、君主の政治状態
Then these are more vague
そうすると、これらはもっと曖昧になります
daily life terms
日常生活的用語
With this political struggle
この政治闘争で
Then during the English Civil War
その後、イギリス南北戦争中に
with this aristocracy
この貴族たちと
Plus one of this sect of various religions
さらに、さまざまな宗教のこの宗派の 1 つ
In fierce confrontation?
激しい対立で？
or not hoping to find
あるいは見つかることを期待していない
we two see or not
私たち二人は見えるか見えないか
find a higher point
より高い点を見つける
what about this time
今回はどうですか
The concept of country has been settled
国の概念が決まった
So what's the difference between him and democracy?
それでは、彼と民主主義の違いは何でしょうか？
Before the concept of the country was settled
国家という概念が固まる前に
The concept of country is not yet the concept of country
国の概念はまだ国の概念ではない
That is to say, when we use the word State in English,
つまり、英語で State という言葉を使うとき、
The one that pops up in our heads
私たちの頭の中に浮かぶのは
associated, that, that, that, that, that semantic
関連付けられた、そのこと、そのこと、その意味論
no country as we speak
私たちが話しているような国はありません
For example, let's talk about the Republic of China
たとえば中華民国について話しましょう
or thinking about the republic of america
あるいはアメリカ共和国について考える
We thought of this certain country
僕らはこのとある国を想った
But the concept of democracy is different
でも民主主義の概念は違う
the concept of democracy
民主主義の概念
it self in greek city-state
それ自体はギリシャの都市国家です
In the first Greek city-states
最初のギリシャの都市国家では
Once a Democracy Experience Is Determined
民主主義の経験が決定されたら
So the political value of democracy
つまり民主主義の政治的価値は
is a bit like China
ちょっと中国に似てる
I'm making an assumption
私は仮定を立てています
Forgive my material if there are historians here
ここに歴史家がいるなら、私の内容を許してください
For example feudal
たとえば封建制
or Jing Tian
ジンティアンとか
This concept existed 2000 years ago
この概念は2000年前に存在しました
So
それで
so it existed as a concept
だからそれは概念として存在した
It was in the 18th century or after the 17th and 8th centuries
それは18世紀か17世紀から8世紀以降でした
it re-emerge
それは再び現れます
it slowly reappears
それはゆっくりと再び現れます
And after two or three centuries of development
そして2、3世紀の発展を経て、
Obtain an overwhelming advantage at the end of the 24th century
24世紀末に圧倒的なアドバンテージを獲得する
So the fact of its coming again
それで、それが再び来るという事実
Not exactly the same as other political concepts
他の政治概念とまったく同じではない
at least in my understanding
少なくとも私の理解では
I hope to be able to tell the difference in a very specific way.
違いを非常に具体的な方法で伝えることができれば幸いです。
so
それで
But the story of democracy
しかし民主主義の話
how to tell this story
この話をどうやって伝えるか
That is to say, democracy started from the city-states of Greece 2,000 years ago
つまり、民主主義は2000年前のギリシャの都市国家から始まったのです。
to modern democracies
現代の民主主義へ
or among countries
あるいは国家間で
we become a democratic country
私たちは民主主義の国になります
or a democratic society
あるいは民主主義社会
Is this story a historical teleology?
この物語は歴史的目的論なのでしょうか？
it's like i'm going to go back and see
戻って見に行くようなものです
Fukuyama said like that
福山さんはそう言ってた
OK let's put this human
OK、この人間を入れましょう
a history of us
私たちの歴史
In pursuit of our autonomy
私たちの自主性を追求して
We pursue this ego governing ourselves and so on
私たちは自分自身を支配するこのエゴを追い求めます。
Then such a kind is regarded as a
このような種類は次のようにみなされます。
as one of our most important
私たちの最も重要なことの一つとして
Is it to discuss a kind of dignity of a person?
それはある種の人間の尊厳について議論するためでしょうか？
Or are we going to use some social
それともソーシャル機能を使うつもりですか
What about a theory of the evolution of value?
価値進化理論についてはどうでしょうか？
I think it is in our present age
それが現代にもあると思う
It's probably not easy to say such a thing
そんなことを言うのは簡単ではないかもしれない
I think democracy is a non-intended process
民主主義は意図しないプロセスだと思う
it is an unintended one
それは意図しないものです
It is an unintentional process
それは意図しないプロセスです
as a researcher of intellectual history
思想史の研究者として
I do not believe in a teleology of history
私は歴史の目的論を信じません
I believe in history
私は歴史を信じます
But what I believe is that in the course of history
しかし私が信じているのは、歴史の流れの中で
Historical agency
歴史庁
the actors of history themselves
歴史の主役たちそのもの
it will have its ideas
それは自分の考えを持っているだろう
Its perceptions can have an impact on its actions
その認識はその行動に影響を与える可能性があります
Of course this effect we cannot say is a
もちろん、この効果はそうとは言えませんが、
a british influence
イギリスの影響
it is complicated
それは複雑です
For example, how do I understand democracy
たとえば、民主主義をどう理解すればよいか
Democracy as I understand it and democracy as you understand it
私が理解する民主主義とあなたが理解する民主主義
If we are not the same, we will conflict
同じでないと衝突してしまう
but no matter what
でも何があっても
I
私
Our actions are consistent with our commitment to democracy
私たちの行動は民主主義への取り組みと一致しています
or other values ​​of this concept are related
またはこの概念の他の値が関連している
So what about such a process?
では、そのようなプロセスはどうでしょうか？
it has several important features
いくつかの重要な機能があります
I have translated it into Chinese in my Hand out
配布資料に中国語に翻訳しました
So I express it in English here
なのでここでは英語で表現します
First
初め
Democracy is a Herman-Newtics
民主主義はハーマン・ニューティックスである
This is probably a rather strange statement.
これはおそらくかなり奇妙な発言です。
I had a discussion with a historian a few days ago
数日前、私は歴史家と議論しました
That is to say, history is a whole world
つまり、歴史は一つの世界なのです
sorry
ごめん
Democracy, the specificity of the presence of democracy that I mentioned earlier
民主主義、先ほど述べた民主主義の存在の特殊性
It's an interesting interpretation of an
興味深い解釈ですね
it has a feature that we call hermeneutics
解釈学と呼ばれる機能があります
Why do we say it has a hermeneutic character?
なぜ解釈学的性格があると言えるのでしょうか?
Because it has a Classical Text
古典的なテキストがあるので、
it has a classical tradition
古典的な伝統がある
classical experience
古典的な経験
The main thing is the politics of Yaris Dorda
重要なのはヤリス・ドルダの政治だ
There is this classical political philosophy
この古典的な政治哲学があります
For Greek democracy at the time
当時のギリシャの民主主義にとって
and various other monarchies
および他のさまざまな君主制
the concept of the monarch
君主の概念
concept of aristocracy concept of aristocracy
貴族制の概念 貴族支配の概念
and the concept of democracy
そして民主主義の概念
It has a very complete analysis
非常に完全な分析が行われています
So it has a text in that place
その場所にテキストがあります
In ancient democracy, there was a text in that place
古代民主主義では、そこにテキストがあった
But it has a contemporary
でもそこには現代性がある
A horizon of historical actors
歴史上の俳優の地平線
horizon we know it is a concept of the whole world
地平線は全世界の概念であることを私たちは知っています
That's when I'm learning about something
そのとき私は何かを学んでいます
an agent an actor
一個agent 一個行動者
either an interpreter or a reader
通訳か読者のどちらか
I probably I didn't read this kalama bless bro before
おそらく私はこのカラマの祝福の兄弟をこれまで読んだことがなかったと思います
I may have some vague idea of ​​the literature of the book
この本の文献について漠然としたアイデアがあるかもしれません
one thing i want to know
一つ知りたいことがある
Well, but my understanding is actually
まあ、でも私の理解は実際には
I have read this novel very thoroughly
私はこの小説をとても徹底的に読みました
To various this inside
この中のいろいろなところへ
A very complex science of a character
キャラクターの非常に複雑な科学
and its dialogue
そしてその対話
Grand Inquisitor etc.
大審問官など
after i understand
理解した後
I can come out and say how I probably understand this book
私は外に出て、私がこの本をどのように理解したかを言うことができます
So is a horizon in this place
この場所にも地平線がある
So this democracy as an interpretation of an experience
つまり、経験の解釈としてのこの民主主義
this is thinking
これは考えています
The level of not wanting is not at the level of reality
欲しくないというレベルは現実のレベルではない
The level of reality certainly has class interests
現実のレベルには確かに階級的利益がある
Then the material struggle and so on
それから物質的な闘争など
this undeniable
これは否定できない
I'm not saying that people are only determined by their ideas
人は自分の考えだけで決まると言っているわけではありません
But the idea exists in this place
でもアイデアはここにある
Then the idea of ​​democracy
それから民主主義の考え方
Its special place is that
その特別な場所は、
it has a classical text
古典的なテキストがあります
there is a classical text in that place
そこには古典のテキストがあります
as a reference
参考として
But an interesting aspect of the nation lies in this place
しかし、この国の興味深い側面はここにあります
It is not like Chinese Jingtian or feudal
中国の景田主義や封建主義とは違います
we say we are in the modern world
私たちは現代世界にいると言います
To put such a system into our modern society
このようなシステムを現代社会に導入するには
that often has a devastating consequence
それはしばしば壊滅的な結果をもたらす
Did democracy have any consequences?
民主主義は何らかの結果をもたらしましたか？
Democracy in the Western world
西側世界の民主主義
also caused great political turmoil
大きな政治的混乱も引き起こした
This several revolutions
この数回転
But it's another interesting one
でも、それがまた面白いんです
a state of change
変化の状態
or a changing look
または見た目の変化
We call it recontactualization
私たちはそれを再連絡と呼んでいます
That is to say, democracy itself in the classical period
つまり、古典期における民主主義そのもの
as an expression of direct democracy
直接民主主義の表現として
After he arrived in modern times he was contactualized again
彼が現代に到着した後、彼は再び接触した
His value is re-converted
彼の価値が再変換される
He transforms into something different than he was
彼は以前とは違う何かに変身する
so what
だから何
The last point is the change of this value of democracy
最後のポイントは、この民主主義の価値観の変化です
It is an innovative transformational idea
それは革新的な変革のアイデアです
That is to say, it is a kind of political value
つまり、一種の政治的価値観です
mine new a way of changing
私の新しい変化の方法
So this process of change in democracy
つまり、民主主義におけるこの変化のプロセスは、
let me emphasize again
もう一度強調させてください
there is no one great
偉い人はいない
great philosopher or great legislator
偉大な哲学者または偉大な立法者
Said that democracy should be like this in modern times
民主主義は現代的なものであるべきだと述べた
It's not the ancient one, it didn't exist
それは古代のものではありません、それは存在しませんでした
it is in the process
それは進行中です
in generations
世代的に
thinkers in the west
西側の思想家
and when it came to the east
そして東に来たとき
Thinkers in the East
東洋の思想家
or among historical actors
または歴史上の俳優の間で
slowly forming a
ゆっくりと形成されていく
what we are now
私たちは今何ですか
Then, in retrospect of the history of thought
そして、思想史を振り返ってみると、
here only know
ここだけが知っている
just a simple one
単純なものだけ
orange this place
ここはオレンジ色
That is to say, if we look at the history of Western thought
つまり、西洋思想史を見てみると、
it has a classical democracy
そこには古典的な民主主義がある
This is what we generally call direct democracy.
これが一般的に直接民主主義と呼ばれるものです。
that's done in greek sorry
それはギリシャ語ですみません
greek city-state
ギリシャの都市国家
Especially the city-state of Athens as a model
特にモデルとなった都市国家アテネ
Then it has the National Assembly and the People's Court
それから国会と人民裁判所があります
Almost always by lottery
ほぼいつも抽選です
I'm sorry, the National Assembly and the People's Court
国会と人民法院、ごめんなさい。
The National Assembly is open to all citizens
国会はすべての国民に開かれています
Then the people's court is very large
それから人民法院は非常に大きいです
is a lottery, almost all Greek institutions
ギリシャのほぼすべての機関は宝くじです
Except for the most important military leaders
最も重要な軍事指導者を除いて
and financial officials
と金融関係者
all by lottery
すべて抽選で
Lottery is a mechanism of democracy
宝くじは民主主義の仕組みです
then other
それからその他
Like the big general I just mentioned
さっき言った大将軍みたいに
or finance officials they use elections
あるいは財務当局者が選挙を利用する
Elections for Greek Democratic Theory
ギリシャ民主主義理論のための選挙
It's a mechanism for an aristocrat
貴族の仕組みだよ
It is completely different from what we think now
今私たちが思っていることとは全く違います
It's an interesting change in a democracy
民主主義における興味深い変化だ
in modern democracy
現代民主主義では
I differentiate it into two
２つに分けてます
That's just a temporary distinction
それは一時的な区別にすぎません
Everyone probably knows
おそらく誰もが知っています
A Democracy I Call Substantive
私が実質的な民主主義と呼ぶもの
This substantive democracy focuses on
この実質的な民主主義は次のことに焦点を当てています。
substantial democracy
実質的な民主主義
It focuses on the concept of democracy or the people
民主主義や人民の概念に焦点を当てています
Then as a substantive concept
それから、実質的な概念としては
it is based on the will
それは意志に基づいています
it strives for equality
それは平等を目指して努力します
Equality is always at the heart of democracy
平等は常に民主主義の中心にあります
most important value
最も重要な価値観
Of course now we
もちろん今、私たちは
Especially the current society in Taiwan
特に現在の台湾社会
everyone is talking about it
誰もがそれについて話しています
or the identity of ruler and ruled
あるいは支配者と被支配者のアイデンティティ
This is a more philosophical expression
これはより哲学的な表現です
identity
身元
which means I don't want to have one
つまり、持ちたくないのです
Perpetual existence also with a group of my comrades
仲間たちとともに永遠に
king or lord
王または主
That's what a comrade looks like
仲間ってそんな感じだよな
what democracy imagines is
民主主義が想像するものは
No one is gay with anyone other than us
私たち以外の誰も同性愛者ではありません
it must be in
それは中にあるはずです
in a process within ourselves
自分自身の中でのプロセスの中で
in the process of democracy
民主主義の過程で
in the political process
政治プロセスの中で
Another concept of democracy is
民主主義のもう一つの概念は、
procedural procedure
手続き手順
it is free
これは無料
We sometimes call it Liberal Democracy
私たちはそれを自由民主主義と呼ぶこともあります
or constitutional democracy
あるいは立憲民主主義
Constitutionalism is well expressed
立憲主義がよく表現されている
this
これ
the meaning of procedure
procedure的意思
that speaks freely
自由に話すのは
is compatible with the constitution
憲政に沿ったものだ
some concepts of liberty we say libertarianism
私たちがリバタリアニズムと呼ぶ自由のいくつかの概念
I'll talk about that later
それについては後で話します
What about procedural concepts?
手続き上の概念についてはどうでしょうか?
it is rational
それは合理的です
in front of will
意志の前で
these are two different things
これらは2つの異なるものです
then it pursues a process of rational deliberation
その後、合理的な熟慮のプロセスを追求します
and then reach a consensus
そして合意に達する
these are two different
これらは二つ違います
modern concept of democracy
現代の民主主義の概念
What about classical democracy?
古典的な民主主義はどうでしょうか？
is intentional
意図的です
So
それで
Let me briefly introduce
簡単に紹介しましょう
The theory of democracy in this classical period
この古典期における民主主義の理論
that same
それと同じ
In our look at Greek political theory
ギリシャの政治理論を見てみる
words in greek political thought
ギリシャの政治思想の言葉
We can distinguish that
私たちはそれを区別できます
how democratic democratic actors understand themselves
民主的な民主的主体は自分自身をどのように理解するか
That is to say your self understanding
つまり、あなたの自己理解です
your self-knowledge
あなたの自己認識
and what do we do with the concept of democracy
そして民主主義の概念をどうするのか
what we call scientific analysis
私たちが科学的分析と呼ぶもの
or academic analysis
または学術的な分析
that democratic self-understanding
その民主的な自己理解
One of the best in Greece
ギリシャで最高のホテルの 1 つ
That is, Perecholus' national business talk is Funeral Oration
それはペレコルスの葬儀の演説です。
It is included in the rest of the physical division
残りの物理部門に含まれます
Among Borobinissa warriors
ボロビニッサの戦士たちの中で
Then one of its contexts is a time in Greece
そして、その背景の一つはギリシャの時代です。
during the battle
戦闘中に
Then there is the messenger of the warrior
そこに戦士の使者がいる
Then this Perecholus was
そしてこのペレコルスは
leader of the greek nation
ギリシャ国家の指導者
So according to the custom at that time
それで当時の風習に従って
This is where these fallen soldiers are buried
ここは戦死した兵士たちが埋葬されている場所です
During this funeral
今回の葬儀の際に
that is to say, made a
つまり、
gave a very famous speech
非常に有名なスピーチをしました
what this speech is about
このスピーチは何についてですか
it's going to inspire
それはインスピレーションを与えるだろう
so it's against this family widow
だからそれはこの家族の未亡人に反対することになる
What about these relatives of the soldier?
兵士の親戚はどうなるのでしょうか？
to tell a story about the Greek nation
ギリシャ国民についての物語を語る
worthy of their relatives
彼らの親戚にふさわしい
For such a circle
そんなサークルのために
a very famous lecturer
とても有名な講師
Of course everyone is interested
もちろんみんな興味あるよ
you can find it for reference
参考として見つけることができます
the Chinese translation
中国語訳
In the Anthology of many nations
多くの国のアンソロジーに
In ethnic Text
民族文書で
Then one of its main
それからそのメインの一つが
actually
実際
He said our system is called a democracy
彼は、私たちのシステムは民主主義と呼ばれていると言いました
because the city-state has a majority of people
都市国家には大多数の国民がいるから
rather than being managed by a handful of people
少数の人によって管理されるのではなく、
We see that when the law resolves its own disputes
法律自体が紛争を解決するとき、
Provides equal justice for all
すべての人に平等な正義を提供する
equality and justice
平等と正義
then in public life
それから公生活では
priority for public office
公職優先
Consider a person's talents
人の才能を考える
rather than his social status
社会的地位よりも
or what class does he belong to etc.
または彼がどのクラスに属しているかなど。
Of course, there is a very small paragraph in the middle of the word.
もちろん、単語の途中に非常に小さな段落があります。
Well but we see a
まあ、しかし、私たちは、
The key concept is
重要なコンセプトは、
Democracy is the rule of the majority
民主主義とは多数決の原則である
So in the future development
ということで今後の展開としては
For the concept of the majority
マジョリティという概念に対して
What priority does he have to climb this
彼はこれを登るのに何を優先しなければなりませんか
he has the legitimacy to rule
彼には統治する正当性がある
This is a key question
これは重要な質問です
So let's look at this now
それでは、今度はこれを見てみましょう
What about Aristotle's theory?
アリストテレスの理論はどうでしょうか？
It is different from the previous rest geography
これまでの休憩地形とは異なります
He is an analysis of what we now call science
彼は私たちが今科学と呼んでいるものの分析です
Analysis of Political Science
政治学の分析
Of course we don't call him political science now
もちろん、今では彼を政治学とは呼びません
Analysis of Political Philosophy or Analysis of Political Theory
政治哲学の分析または政治理論の分析
it is the experience
それは経験です
it when aristotle collected
アリストテレスが収集したとき
Constitutions of three or four hundred small Greek city-states
ギリシャの 300 ～ 400 の小都市国家の憲法
Then it analyzes the logic of democracy
次に民主主義の論理を分析します
it analyzes the logic of nobility
貴族の論理を分析する
It divides Greek society without a monarchical element
君主制の要素なしにギリシャ社会を分断する
This will be mentioned later
これについては後述します
so what
だから何
It proposes a very complete text
非常に完全なテキストを提案しています
For Westerners, this structure
西洋人にとってこの構造は
understanding at that time
その時の理解
and for us modern times in the West
そして西洋の現代の私たちにとって
Democracy regenerates an influence
民主主義は影響力を回復する
It acts as a key influence
重要な影響力を持っています
let's see what it says
それが何を言っているか見てみましょう
Then it appears to be a
すると、それは次のようです
very simple classification
非常に単純な分類
then it scales with the number of rulers
その後、ルーラーの数に応じてスケールされます
I think many of the guests may know
ゲストの方もご存知の方も多いと思いますが、
It uses a single individual minority and majority
単一の少数派と多数派を利用する
This is a quantitative standard
これは定量的な基準です
Then it divides into its rulers
それから支配者たちに分かれる
Is it based on common interests
それは共通の利益に基づいていますか
or it follows the ruler's self-interest
あるいは支配者の私利私欲に従う
Divided into government and debate
政府と議論に分かれる
It is a correct system and a
それは正しいシステムであり、
perverted is a formal body of corruption
変態は正式な腐敗の体である
Then he divides into this single body which is the monarch body
それから彼は君主の体であるこの単一の体に分かれます
good formal
良いフォーマル
A good orthodox is a monarch orthodox
優れた正統性は君主制の正統性である
aristocratic and republican
貴族と共和党
I'll talk later
後で話します
So the body of the defense is the founder is terranine
つまり、防御の本体は創設者はテラニンです
This is sometimes translated into a tyrant
これは暴君と訳されることもあります
But terranine is a builder
しかし、テラニンはビルダーです
It is a translation that is more neutral than ours
私たちの翻訳よりも中立的な翻訳です
But everyone knows that it is terranine
でもそれがテラニンであることは誰もが知っています
oligarch is arigaki
オリガルヒはアリガキだ
or arigaki
またはアリガキ
But what we saw was interesting in this place
でも、この場所で見たものは面白かった
The main body of democracy is placed in the main body of debate
民主主義の本体は議論の本体に置かれる
that is to say
つまり
His logical circularity does not mean that the monarchy, aristocracy, and democracy
彼の論理的循環性は、君主制、貴族制、民主主義を意味するものではありません。
Founder or tyrant oligarch
創設者または暴君寡頭政治家
or something to put here
またはここに置くもの
There is also Aristotle's political theory
アリストテレスの政治理論もある
Political Theories Influencing the West for Two Thousand Years
二千年にわたり西洋に影響を与えた政治理論
We say he might have some vibe of some democracy
私たちは彼が民主主義の雰囲気を持っているかもしれないと言います
Well, but you go to see Aristotle
まあ、でもアリストテレスに会いに行くのは
His articles are not many
彼の記事はそれほど多くない
for every regime
あらゆる政権にとって
his non-existent monarchy for greece
ギリシャに存在しない彼の君主制
he clearly pointed out
彼ははっきりと指摘した
The virtue of his ruler is an extraordinary virtue
彼の統治者の美徳は並外れた美徳である
use one of us
私たちのうちの一人を使ってください
A metaphor well understood by the Chinese
中国人によく理解される比喩
For example, Dahe Zhishui
たとえば、大和志水
Yamato was three generations before
ヤマトは三世代前
Great and before is kindness
素晴らしい、そしてそれ以前は優しさです
But Da Yu's virtue is so high
しかし、ダユの徳はとても高いです
his achievement is so big
彼の功績はとても大きいです
make the people willing to regard him as a monarch
人々が彼を君主とみな​​してくれるようにする
this is a monarchy
これは君主制です
That is to say, the monarch's morality
つまり君主の道徳
basis of legitimacy
正当性の根拠
is a single individual
一人の個人です
a very special virtue
非常に特別な美徳
the aristocracy is
貴族階級は
The concept of virtual virtue
仮想美徳の概念
then democracies
それから民主主義
We see that his actual analysis is
彼の実際の分析は次のとおりであることがわかります。
equal to the liberty
自由に等しい
The two principles are equality and liberty
二つの原則は平等と自由です
So Aristotle for
したがって、アリストテレスにとっては、
Analysis of Democracy
民主主義の分析
It's not as simple as we are now
今ほど単純ではない
look
見て
You are biased towards him
あなたは彼に対して偏見を持っています
Of course there is a little bias
もちろん多少の偏見はありますが
Aristotle thought
アリストテレスの考え
What does he think is the best form of government?
彼は最良の政府形態とは何だと考えていますか?
It's this kind of regime mixed with this
こういう体制とこれが混在しているんです。
so
それで
What about the rule of many people in the regime?
政権内の多数の人々の支配についてはどうですか？
He's called a republic called a Polity
彼はポリティと呼ばれる共和国と呼ばれています
The concept of Polity is a mixture of oligarchy and democracy
政治の概念は寡頭制と民主主義を組み合わせたものである
He believes that oligarchy and democracy are the same
彼は寡頭制と民主主義は同じだと信じている
At that time the Greek two class struggle
当時ギリシャの二階級闘争
The two most powerful classes in conflict
対立する 2 つの最も強力な階級
a class of nobility
貴族の階級
The worse state is the oligarch
もっと悪い国家は寡頭政治だ
Then the other is the democratic majority
そうすると、もう一方は民主的な多数派です
Bad state is democracy
悪い国家とは民主主義だ
what about these two
この二人はどうですか
It's all over
すべて終わった
This fate means the middle of the mean
この運命は平均値の中間を意味する
Aristotle's philosophy
アリストテレスの哲学
It's a bit like the Confucian philosophy in China.
これは中国の儒教哲学に似ています。
The golden mean
黄金の平均
So these two are Access
つまり、この2つはAccessです
The pursuit of wealth or virtue is not considered
富や美徳の追求は考慮されない
pursuit of wealth or virtue
富や美徳の追求
he both he all he is a good thing
彼は両方とも彼は良いことだ
Equality and liberty are also a good thing
平等と自由も良いことだ
But what?
でも何？
they chased
彼らは追いかけた
After it's over, it becomes over
終わったら終わりになる
After that, we need to put two
その後、2つを置く必要があります
through some mechanism
いくつかのメカニズムを通じて
This is the city-state
これが都市国家だ
What about these mechanisms?
これらのメカニズムはどうなるのでしょうか？
mix it up
混ぜあわせる
then become the so-called republic
その後いわゆる共和制となる
What about the concept of Aristotle?
アリストテレスの概念はどうでしょうか？
It affected this across the West
西部全域に影響を与えた
a political thought
政治的思想
But what I just said
でも今私が言ったことは
it actually to some extent
実際にはある程度は
There is a stigmatization of democracy
民主主義に対する汚名が存在する
But this stigmatization
しかし、この偏見は
Stigmatization in Chinese
中国語でのスティグマ化
pretty ugly
かなり醜い
stigma
汚名
That is to say, it actually
つまり、実は、
missing a label in that place
その場所のラベルがありません
But is there a theoretical reason for this label?
しかし、このラベルには理論的な理由があるのでしょうか?
Let's see there's actually a reason
実際には理由があることを見てみましょう
it says so
それはそう言う
it says democracy
民主主義って言うんだよ
是the rule of many
多くの人たちのルール
with a view to the advantage of many only
多くの人だけの利益を考えて
That is to say, according to its political system and defense system
つまり、その政治制度と防衛制度によれば、
if this category
このカテゴリの場合
What about democratic rule?
民主主義の統治はどうでしょうか？
is majority rule
多数決です
But it only takes care of its own interests
しかし、それは自分の利益だけを考慮します
Then we will still ask
それから私たちはまだ尋ねます
this right
これは正しい
our democratic majority vote
私たちの民主的な多数決
Then cast out one I am now
それから今の私を追い出しなさい
The political party you are supporting is a democratic process
あなたが支持している政党は民主的なプロセスです
Aristotle didn't see it that way
アリストテレスはそのようには考えていませんでした
Well, but we don't care about this for now
まあ、でも今のところは気にしません
focus on this place
この場所に焦点を当ててください
Many is in Aristotle's system
多くはアリストテレス体系にあります
it's just a part
それはほんの一部です
So democracy is either aristocrats or monarchs
つまり民主主義とは貴族か君主のどちらかである
it's all just a part
それはすべてほんの一部です
This part allows democracy itself to have an advantage in numbers
この部分により民主主義自体が数の面で有利になる
we are the majority
私たちが多数派です
or most of us
あるいは私たちのほとんどが
we should have the legitimacy to rule
私たちは統治する正当性を持っているべきです
What about the legitimacy?
正当性についてはどうですか？
it wipes it out
それはそれを一掃します
or weaken it
もしくは弱めるか
it's about you
それはあなたのことです
you are all part of the regime
あなた方全員が政権の一員です
You are just a part of the cost
あなたはコストの一部にすぎません
you as a part
あなたもその一部として
You said you were going to be the ruler with a few nobles
あなたは数人の貴族を率いて統治者になるつもりだと言いました
Suppose he is virtuous
彼は徳があると仮定しよう
This place is where we see the difference between ancient times and modern times
ここは古代と現代の違いを見る場所です
According to Aristotle, a minority elite
アリストテレスによれば、少数派のエリートは
They are of higher virtue
彼らはより高い徳を持っています
or better
それ以上の
We must have the ability to rule
私たちは統治する能力を持たなければなりません
it constitutes a claim to a justifiable dominion
それは正当な支配権の主張を構成します
But in our modern
しかし、私たちの現代では、
we do not accept the concept
私たちはその概念を受け入れません
We'll see why later
その理由は後でわかります
So
それで
one
一個
Another important change
もう一つの重要な変更
He said this Many is always poor
彼はこう言いました、多くの人はいつも貧しいのです
that is
あれは
it has an iron law
それには鉄の法則がある
Have you ever seen anything in this world
この世界で何かを見たことはありますか
in any society
どの社会でも
rich people are few
裕福な人は少ない
the poor are the majority
貧しい人が大多数である
He said there is no such society
そんな社会は存在しないと彼は言った
So Many will always be poor or common people
非常に多くの人は常に貧しいか庶民です
so we put him
それで私たちは彼を置きました
this is his words
これは彼の言葉です
we replace him
私たちが彼の代わりをします
So his labeling of democracy
つまり、彼の民主主義に対するレッテル貼りは、
that is
あれは
Democracy is the rule of the poor
民主主義は貧しい者の支配である
with a view to the delineable poor home
描写可能な貧しい家庭を目指して
So
それで
This is the whole of the West until modern times
これが近代までの西洋全体です
for democracy
民主主義のために
after the pro-democracy demonstrations
民主化デモの後
what people remember
人々が覚えていること
Probably just a Greek city-state over 200 years old
おそらく200年以上の歴史を持つ単なるギリシャの都市国家
very confusing
とても混乱するような
call back and forth
何度も電話をかける
So
それで
Even now we look at the history of Western political thought
今でも西洋の政治思想の歴史を見てみますと、
In fact, there is a very interesting example that says
実際、次のような非常に興味深い例があります。
You go to see Greek democracy
あなたはギリシャの民主主義を見に行きます
You can't see democracy itself
民主主義そのものが見えない
Except the rest body is what I just cited
残りの本体は私が今引用したものであることを除いて
this fumal ration
このフマル配給
you don't see a theorist
理論家が見えない
For this democracy propose a
この民主主義のために、次のことを提案します。
how about a system
システムはどうですか
A justification of war promise
戰許式的一個justification
why
なぜ
because Greek democracy
ギリシャ民主主義だから
Just like our current democracy
私たちの現在の民主主義と同じように
Most of the action of democracy takes place in that field
民主主義の活動のほとんどはその分野で行われます
all at that civic assembly
すべてあの市民集会で
in the people's assembly
人民集会で
one of them trained themselves to speak
彼らのうちの一人は話すように訓練しました
an ability to stop
止める能力
talking about what we should do now
私たちは今何をすべきですか
What attitude should we adopt towards China
私たちは中国に対してどのような態度を取るべきか
what should we do to america
アメリカに何をすべきか
What should we do with American cows
アメリカ牛をどうするべきか
I'm going to convince a
私は説得するつもりです
sometimes one in ten thousand
時には1万分の1
a place for gatherings
集まりの場所
this is greek from sophist
これはソフィストからのギリシャ語です
That is to say, the self-reproach
つまり、自責の念
training this public one says
訓練をしているとこの公の者は言う
A technique for a public speech
人前でスピーチするためのテクニック
We now see the familiar
今ではおなじみのものが見えてきました
This stigma went to one of the Roman era
この汚名はローマ時代にまで遡りました
Greek historian called Polybius
ポリュビオスというギリシャの歴史家
Polybius made a correction
ポリュビアスが修正しました
This revision affected the later Western
この改訂は後の西部劇に影響を与えた
He put the democratic court into the political system
彼は政治制度に民主法廷を導入した
At this time, democracy is in the context of Rome
現時点では、民主主義はローマの文脈にあります
So the Romans were basically gay oligarchs
つまりローマ人は基本的に同性愛者の寡頭政治だった
The power of his nobility is still great
彼の貴族の力は依然として偉大です
But the concept of people in Rome
しかし、ローマの人々の概念
is a legal concept
法的な概念です
So they themselves for this
それで彼ら自身がこのために
The Three Elements of Monarchy, Nobility and Democracy
君主制、貴族、民主主義の三要素
It is a more balanced consideration
よりバランスのとれた検討です
So Polybius is here
それでポリビアスがここにいます
Orthodoxy
正統派
It is the right system
それは正しいシステムです
Then variants are no longer democracy.
そうなると、バリアントはもはや民主主義ではなくなります。
He called him coined a word called mob regime
彼は暴徒体制という造語を作って彼を呼んだ
Then this is more in line with our imagination
そうすれば、これは私たちの想像にもっと一致します
democracy is good
民主主義は良いことだ
That mutant mob, right?
あのミュータント暴徒ですよね？
each has good and each has bad
それぞれに良い点があり、それぞれに悪い点がある
what about the really good stuff
本当に良いものはどうですか
Just now Aristotle had only two things mixed
たった今、アリストテレスは 2 つのことだけを混ぜ合わせていました
that is
あれは
The de facto nobles and commoners in Greece at that time
当時のギリシャの事実上の貴族と平民
Also ample filling for both factions
両陣営の充実した内容も充実
two classes
2つのクラス
What now
今、何
It creates another new concept that is
それはもう一つの新しい概念を生み出します。
A mixed constitution is three mixed
混合構成とは3つが混合したものです
Of course it's because Rome
もちろんローマだから
He himself before becoming a republic
彼自身は共和国になる前に
there is a shift in monarchy
君主制の変遷がある
So
それで
re-enter the modern
再び現代に入る
Actually I need to go faster
本当はもっと早く行く必要があるんだ
i found out that time is not enough
時間が足りないことが分かりました
So
それで
i want to talk a little bit
少し話したいです
That is in Aristotle's concept of politics
それはアリストテレスの政治概念にある
i will call it
電話します
Xunhua Democracy
宣華民主主義
That is to say, democracy is a
つまり、民主主義というのは、
is a difficult one to control
コントロールするのが難しいものです
a political process
政治的プロセス
So it has to cycle
したがって、循環する必要があります
So the classical theory
したがって、古典的な理論では、
Its cycle concept is called regimen
そのサイクルの概念を養生法といいます。
called politics
政治という
is pollution
汚染です
polythea
ポリテア
This concept is sometimes used in English translations
この概念は英語の翻訳でも使用されることがあります。
translate it into constitution
それを憲法に翻訳する
not a good translation
良い翻訳ではありません
Now that the better one is translated into regimen
より良いものが養生法に変換されるようになりました
Although sometimes in contemporary politics
時には現代政治でも
Regime also represents the concept of regime
レジームは体制の概念も表します
but we are
しかし私たちは
I usually translate it into politics
私はそれを政治に置き換えることが多い
for a very specific purpose
非常に特殊な目的のために
So Aristotle for politics
つまり、政治におけるアリストテレス
He brought it up to say
彼はそれを持ち出してこう言いました
for official position
公的な地位のために
Especially this authoritative official position
特にこの権威ある公式見解
an arrangement of a political order
政治的秩序の取り決め
Then the point is the next decision
となると、重要なのは次の決断だ
He said that no matter what type of city-state
彼は、どんな都市国家であろうとも言った。
His authority must rest with a ruling body
彼の権威は統治機関に委ねられなければならない
That is to say, in terms of classical theory
つまり、古典理論的に言えば、
The very machine world we just talked about
まさに今話した機械の世界
Classification that looks very machine-bound
非常に機械に依存しているように見える分類
His focus is on
彼の焦点は次のとおりです
a group capable of forming a mixed rule
混合ルールを形成できるグループ
So out of six or three of these pure regimes
つまり、これらの純粋な体制のうち 6 つまたは 3 つのうち、
He said, for example, that democracy is
彼は、例えば、民主主義とは次のように述べています。
Democracy is the authority of the common people
民主主義は庶民の権威である
An oligarchy is a minority with authority
寡頭制とは権威を持つ少数派である
Well but what they hope to do
まあ、しかし彼らが望んでいることは
this mixed constitution
この混合憲法
His purpose is to bring democracy
彼の目的は民主主義をもたらすことです
Democracy into a mechanism for a balance of power
民主主義をパワーバランスのメカニズムに
is a balance of power
力のバランスです
So whether it's oligarchs or democracies
寡頭政治であろうと民主主義であろうと
In Aristotle there are only two powers
アリストテレスでは権力は二つしかない
or royal aristocrats
もしくは王侯貴族
It's Malaysia and Astaksi
マレーシアとアスタクシです
Plus the three forces of democracy
加えて民主主義の 3 つの力
Three groups of Dingli
ディングリの 3 つのグループ
This is from the Western period
これは西洋時代のものです
A heart of an art of classical politics
古典的な政治芸術の核心
The entirety of Western politics predates modern times
西洋政治全体は近代以前に遡る
It's basically clouded by this analysis
この分析では基本的に曇っている
that is to say
つまり
If you have read Plato's Republic
プラトンの国家を読んだことのある方
It's Utopia
それはユートピアです
you will see a
が表示されます
We are called the Guardian Model
私たちはガーディアンモデルと呼ばれています
that is
あれは
So the concept of politics in the West is the balance of power
つまり、西洋の政治の概念はパワーバランスです
It is not an
それはではありません
That is to say, politics should have a professional
つまり政治には専門家がいるはずだ
this ruler with true knowledge
この統治者は真の知識を持っている
or defenders to rule over us
あるいは私たちを支配する擁護者たち
not such a concept
そんな概念ではない
when you look at plato
プラトンを見ると
You'll see another very specific concept
別の非常に具体的な概念が表示されます
But what about that concept?
しかし、その概念についてはどうでしょうか？
In the development of the West, it is not the main
西洋の発展において、それはメインではありません
The mainstream was developed by Aristotle and Rome
主流はアリストテレスとローマによって開発されました
This republic and the concept of mixed constitutionalism
この共和国と混合立憲主義の概念
So I'm going to move on now to our comparison
それでは、比較に入ります
actually takes more time
実際にはもっと時間がかかります
modern democracy and competition
現代の民主主義と競争
then in my mind
それから私の心の中で
or in my interpretation
あるいは私の解釈では
What about modern democracy itself?
現代民主主義そのものはどうなのだろうか？
it begets itself because of its competitors
競合他社のおかげで自らが生まれる
a repositioning
位置変更
a new identification
新しい身分証明書
So this competitor followed the modern
つまり、この競合他社は現代の
A development in different phases of this politics
この政治のさまざまな段階での展開
Then the earliest ones are State Building and Nation
それから最も古いものは国家建設と国家です
Tell us about nation building and democracy building
国づくりと民主主義づくりについて教えてください
What about the construction of this country and the construction of democracy?
この国の建設と民主主義の構築はどうなるのでしょうか？
Let the concept of democracy revisit Monarchy and Aristocracy
民主主義の概念を君主制と貴族制に再考しましょう
These two things launched a new wave of a struggle
これら 2 つのことが闘争の新たな波を引き起こしました
It's different from the ancient struggle
昔の争いとは違う
what about after this fight
この戦いの後はどうなるのか
yes
はい
Compared with the later liberalism
その後の自由主義と比べて
That is, we will see constitutionalism versus despotism
つまり、立憲主義と専制主義の対立が分かるだろう。
this concept
このコンセプト
A Concept of Despotism is a Novelty Pro Concept
専制主義の概念は斬新なプロの概念です
Its Aristotelian system does not exist
アリストテレスの体系は存在しない
the word is greek
その言葉はギリシャ語です
but it didn't exist
しかしそれは存在しませんでした
We will see this word later
この言葉は後で見ます
It has an influence on China
中国にも影響力あるよ
Because authoritarian politics refers to Chinese style
権威主義政治は中国式だから
one politics of the monarch
君主の一つの政治
That is what Montes said about
モンテスが言っていたのはそういうことだった
Then in the second half of the nineteenth century
そして19世紀後半には
a contender for the last wave of democracy
民主主義の最後の波の候補者
It is the social revolution
それは社会革命です
When it comes to Marx and the socialist revolution
マルクスと社会主義革命の時代です
Generated another wave of democracy versus dictatorship
民主主義対独裁制の新たな波を生み出した
the concept of dictatorship
独裁制の概念
Or later when translated into this
または後でこれに翻訳すると
dictatorship of the proteria
プロテリアの独裁政権
is the proletariat
プロレタリアートです
officially translated as dictatorship
公式には独裁と訳される
But the word dictatorship
しかし、独裁という言葉は
In fact, it is better translated as dictatorship
実際、独裁制と訳した方が適切です。
But that topic probably won't be discussed today.
しかし、その話題はおそらく今日は議論されないでしょう。
then i'll go back
それから戻ります
The first important context is democracy
最初の重要な背景は民主主義です
its first
その最初の
The first week is related to the modern sovereign state
最初の週は現代の主権国家に関するものです
The concept of sovereignty is very familiar to us
主権の概念は私たちにとって非常に馴染みのあるものです
But the first definition of sovereignty was in
しかし、主権の最初の定義は、
not only in the six volumes of treatise on states
国家に関する6巻の論文だけではない
Six Books on the Commonwealth
連邦に関する 6 冊の本
a definition it proposes
それが提案する定義
Around 16, 16, 70 years
16、16、70年くらい
it says that sovereignty is owned by the political community
主権は政治共同体にあると言う
absolute and permanent right
絶対的かつ永久的な権利
Absolute and perpetual
絶対的かつ永久的
These two properties
この 2 つのプロパティ
Then this attribute is in addition to absolute and puppetual
この属性は、絶対的および人形的属性に加えて、
I just talk to you today
今日はただあなたに話すだけです
It also adds a very important thing to the discussion
また、議論に非常に重要なことが追加されます
called indivisible
不可分と呼ばれる
Indivisible?
不可分？
Democracy and nobility and monarchy
民主主義と貴族と君主制
it produced a different one theory one
それは別の理論を生み出しました
not just theory
単なる理論ではなく
that is to say an actual
つまり実際の
A change in the arrangement of our political system
私たちの政治制度の仕組みの変化
It is because sovereignty is indivisible
主権は不可分だから
So it overturns
それでひっくり返る
The classical common
古典的なコモン
he's a balance of power vs a mixed one
彼は力のバランスと混合の力を持っています
a concept of constitutionalism
立憲主義の概念
That concept is mixing and balancing
そのコンセプトは混合とバランスです
Then a topic that gave rise to a whole new theory
その後、まったく新しい理論を生み出したトピック
So there can only be three forms of a sovereign state
したがって、主権国家には 3 つの形態しかあり得ない
So there are no longer six
だからもう6人はいない
In terms of HOPS, only monarchy, aristocracy and democracy
HOPSに関しては、君主制、貴族制、民主主義のみ
The so-called tyrant is just you don't like the monarchy
いわゆる暴君というのは君主制が気に入らないだけだ
The so-called mob is nothing but
いわゆるモブにほかなりません
you
あなた
That is to say you go to say this person
つまり、この人に言いに行くということです
I don't like democracy
私は民主主義が好きではありません
say no three things
3つのことを言わない
sorry
ごめん
There are no six things, only three things
6 つのものはなく、3 つのものだけです
what about this time
今回はどうですか
What about monarchy and aristocracy?
君主制と貴族制はどうでしょうか？
they are about to establish
彼らは確立しようとしている
Who is the sovereign in this struggle?
この闘争の主権者は誰でしょうか？
in the age of absolutism
絶対主義の時代に
the most important one
最も重要なもの
a political issue
政治上的一個議題
but this time
しかし今回は
yields a classical theory
古典的な理論が得られます
A problem that doesn't actually arise
実際には起こらない問題
people are diverse
人は多様です
People, we are now, we have one hundred and fifty or sixty people here
皆さん、私たちは今、ここには150人か60人がいます。
Then there are more than 22 million people in Taiwan
台湾には2200万人以上の人がいる
right
右
Then among the Greek city-states
それからギリシャの都市国家の間では
In his heyday, he had about 50,000 people
全盛期には約5万人がいた
but no matter how many people
でも何人でも
He will not appear in the same field at the same time
彼は同じフィールドに同時に現れることはありません
How can a multitude of peoples become what we are if we say
もし私たちがこう言ったら、どうして多くの人々が私たちのようになることができますか?
We want the sovereignty of democracy by democracy
私たちは民主主義による民主主義の主権を望んでいます
This concept of sovereignty is similar to that of Aristotle
この主権の概念はアリストテレスの概念に似ています
Talking about the ruling group is different
支配グループについて話すのは違う
Well, at this time, this is what the Chinese have just encountered
さて、現時点で、これは中国人がちょうど遭遇したものです
A confusion in the concept of democracy
民主主義の概念の混乱
That is to say, what is the so-called principle of democracy in this democracy?
つまり、この民主主義におけるいわゆる民主主義の原則とは何でしょうか。
what is the main reason
主な理由は何ですか
Then there is another topic at this time
それから今回は別の話題があります
I spend a little time here
ここで少し時間を過ごします
Then it will be a little bit more technical
それから、もう少し技術的な話になります
The rise of the sovereign state coincided with the social contract
主権国家の台頭は社会契約と同時に起こった
social contract earlier
もっと前の社会契約
But the previous social contract was more religious
しかし、以前の社会契約はより宗教的でした
So we're not talking about the social contract today
だから今日は社会契約について話しているのではありません
The concept of dominant country
支配国の概念
What about the combination of the two concepts of the host country?
開催国の2つのコンセプトを組み合わせるとどうなるでしょうか？
at hobbs
ホッブズで
Is a
です
I think it is an ideal theory
理想論だと思う
The most distributed and best system
最も分散された最良のシステム
let's not talk
話さないようにしましょう
that is
あれは
The most compact system
最もコンパクトなシステム
Hobbes proposed the state of nature
ホッブズは自然状態を提唱した
i don't know how many guests
ゲストが何人か分かりません
Know
知る
but
しかし
He presupposes equality
彼は平等を前提としている
This is a core concept
これが核となるコンセプトです
people are equal
人々は平等です
in classical theory
古典理論では
he is not equal
彼は平等ではない
people are different
人は違う
and there is inequality
そして不平等が存在する
Your ability to pursue mathematical knowledge is better than mine
あなたの数学的知識を追求する能力は私より優れています
Your ability to pursue knowledge in the machine world is better than mine
機械の世界で知識を追求するあなたの能力は私より優れています
So you are born unequal
だから君は不平等に生まれてきたんだ
So he is in a different field
つまり彼は違う分野にいるのです
he can win
彼は勝つことができる
He can be in that field
彼はその分野になれる
become a good one
良いものになる
There is the same presupposition in politics
政治でも同じ前提がある
But
しかし
Hobbes' state of nature
ホッブズの自然状態
very interesting premise of equality
平等に関する非常に興味深い前提
but his equality
しかし彼の平等
not equality in the moral sense
道徳的な意味での平等ではない
so he is saying
だから彼は言っている
in a state of nature
自然の状態で
Although we have physical differences
体格差はあっても
Not everyone has the same strength
誰もが同じ強さを持っているわけではない
it is impossible not to accept
受け入れないことは不可能です
But each has a similar chance of killing everyone else
しかし、それぞれが他の全員を殺す可能性は同じです
destroy others
他人を破壊する
That is to say, the strongest person
つまり最強
when he sleeps
彼が寝ているとき
i could stone it to death
石を投げて死ぬこともできる
so he don't bully me
だから彼は私をいじめないでください
If you say it, you say it
あなたがそれを言うなら、あなたはそれを言います
if you tie me up now
今私を縛ってくれたら
I can't run of course I obey you
もちろん逃げられないよ、従うよ
But you want me to ask you to sleep
でもあなたは私に寝てほしいと言うのですか
I can't cut the rope and run away
ロープを切って逃げることはできない
this has to be justified
これは正当化されなければなりません
So one of Hobbes' premise is that
ホッブスの前提の 1 つは次のとおりです。
everyone he destroys everyone else's heritage
彼は皆、他の人の遺産を破壊する
This created a generalized mutual fear
これにより、一般的な相互恐怖が生じました
Then he is in an unstable state
それから彼は不安定な状態にあります
what about this time
今回はどうですか
His natural state is called a state of war
彼の自然な状態は戦争状態と呼ばれます
Well, I don't think we'll talk much about this
まあ、これについてはあまり話すことはないと思います
But people fight each other
しかし人々は互いに争う
But Hobbes told a
しかし、ホッブズはこう言いました。
Maybe it's our modern reaction
おそらくそれは私たちの現代の反応です
He said the fear of death
彼は死の恐怖について言いました
fear of death
死の恐怖
you are afraid to hate
あなたは憎むことを恐れています
you don't want you to sleep
眠ってほしくないのですか
you are already in heaven
あなたはすでに天国にいる
or face it in hell
さもなければ地獄に直面する
Then he let hit this place
それから彼はこの場所を襲わせました
Please pay attention to this word
この言葉に注目してください